Guide to the Frank J. Donner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Subject Files, 1941-1992; Series III
  - Committee In Solidarity with the People of El Salvador (CISPES) [includes material regarding Center for Constitutional Rights]
    - Congressional testimony, 1987-1991 (Box 32, Folder 104 - 107)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 32, Folder 108)
    - Court transcripts and documents
      - General, 1988, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 109 - 110)
      - Chicago CISPES, 1991-1992 (Box 32, Folder 111 - 112)
    - FBI documents, 1984, 1988, undated (Box 32, Folder 113 - 114)
    - Newsletters, 1986-1988 (Box 32, Folder 115)
    - Notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 116)
    - "Selected Headquarters CISPES Documents", undated (Box 33, Folder 117)
    - Varelli, Frank [affidavit], 1987 (Box 33, Folder 118)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983-1990 (Box 33, Folder 119)
  - Committee to Prevent Nuclear War, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 120)
  - Committee to Stop Chemical Atrocities, undated (Box 33, Folder 121)
  - Common Cause, undated (Box 33, Folder 122)
  - Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA)
    - General (Box 33, Folder 123)
    - CPUSA v. J. Howard McGrath, et al., undated (Box 33, Folder 124 - 125)
    - CPUSA v. Subversive Activities Control Board, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 126)
  - Connecticut Civil Liberties Union, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 127)
  - Counter Spy [publication information], undated (Box 33, Folder 128)
  - Covert Action Information Bulletin, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 129)
  - Data Center ["New Right Monitor Update," Sept 1982] (Box 33, Folder 130)
  - The Defender Magazine [publicity], undated (Box 33, Folder 131)
  - Dohrn, Bernadine, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 132)
  - Dowling, Thomas [transcript for "Contra Priest" news special by KRON, San Francisco], 1987 (Box 33, Folder 133)
  - Durr, Clifford, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 134)
  - Ellingswood, Herbert E. [nominee for Attorney General], 1984-1986 (Box 33, Folder 135)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation
    - Congressional oversight
      - Clippings, 1975-1976, undated (Box 33, Folder 136)
      - Writings, undated (Box 33, Folder 137)
      - Miscellaneous, 1975, undated (Box 33, Folder 138)
    - Guidelines for the Use of Surveillance, 1962, 1980-1981, undated (Box 33, Folder 139)
    - "Inside the FBI" [transcript of CBS news broadcast] (Box 34, Folder 140)
    - Library Awareness Program, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 141)
    - Webster, William H. [statement before the Senate Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism], 1982 (Box 34, Folder 142)
    - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 143)
  - Federal Communications Commission, 1987-1988, undated (Box 34, Folder 144)
  - Federation of Southern Cooperatives, undated (Box 34, Folder 145)
  - Fermia, Francis Thomas, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 146)
  - Field Foundation, 1976-1979 (Box 34, Folder 147)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 148)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 149 - 151)
  - Freedom to See [documentary film re: freedom of expression], 1991 (Box 34, Folder 152)
  - The Freedom Writer, 1986-1989 (Box 34, Folder 153)
  - Fund for Open Information and Accountability, 1981-1987, undated (Box 34, Folder 154)
  - Fundamentalists Anonymous, 1987-1989, undated (Box 34, Folder 155 - 156)
  - Gilden, Katya Alpert [memorial booklet], 1991 (Box 34, Folder 157)
  - Ginsburg, Douglas, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 158)
  - Government Accountability Project, undated (Box 34, Folder 159)
  - Greensboro Civil Rights Fund, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 160)
  - Greensboro Justice Fund, undated (Box 34, Folder 161)
  - Group Research Report, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 162)
  - Group Watch [profiles on the Western Goals Foundation and the World Anti-Communist League], undated (Box 34, Folder 163 - 164)
  - Haase, Edward
    - Clippings, undated (Box 34, Folder 165)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 166)
    - Court documents, 1985-1986 (Box 34, Folder 167 - 168)
  - Hard Times, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 169)
  - Harrisburg Seven
    - Clippings, 1970-1973 (Box 35, Folder 170 - 179)
    - Court documents, 1971-1972, undated (Box 35, Folder 180 - 193)
    - Court documents, 1971-1972, undated (Box 36, Folder 194 - 215)
    - Defense Committee, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 216)
    - Gray, Francine [address to the Democratic Town Committee of Newtown, Connecticut], 1972 (Box 36, Folder 217)
    - Notes [Daniel Berrigan], 1970 (Box 37, Folder 218 - 220)
    - Television transcript [CBS news], 1971 (Box 37, Folder 221)
  - Haymarket Collective ["Notes on Security"], undated (Box 37, Folder 222)
  - Heads Up, 1964-1965 (Box 37, Folder 223)
  - Helsinki Watch
    See: Series III. Subject Files, 1941-1992 Folder 337
  - Heritage Foundation, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 224)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities, 1955-1962, undated (Box 37, Folder 225)
  - House Subcommittee on Civil Service, "Index to Clippings of Alleged Ethics Violations by Reagan Administration Appointees", 1987 (Box 37, Folder 226)
  - I. F. Stone's Weekly, 1953-1967 (Box 37, Folder 227 - 228)
  - Institute for Media Analysis, Inc. [Conference: Anti-Communism and the United States: History and Consequences], 1988 (Box 37, Folder 229)
  - Institute on Religion and Democracy, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 230)
  - Internal Revenue Service [notes on files], undated (Box 37, Folder 231)
  - Iran/Contra
    - Mailings, 1985-1987 (Box 37, Folder 232)
    - Memoranda, 1985-1987 (Box 37, Folder 233)
    - Notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 234)
    - Reports, 1985, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 235 - 238)
  - Jewish Defense League
    - Clippings, 1971-1974, undated (Box 38, Folder 239)
    - Legal documents, 1972-1973, undated (Box 38, Folder 240 - 251)
    - Notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 252)
    - Wiretap transcripts, 1971 (Box 38, Folder 253 - 254)
    - Writings, undated (Box 38, Folder 255)
  - Karpuk, Matrona [deportation proceedings], 1954 (Box 39, Folder 256)
  - Kennedy, Anthony M. [report compiled by the Nation Institute], 1987 (Box 39, Folder 257 - 258)
  - Labor Youth League [court documents], 1953 (Box 39, Folder 259)
  - Law Enforcement Intelligence Unit, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 260)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights Under Law, 1985-1986 (Box 39, Folder 261 - 262)
  - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, Helsinki Watch. "Mother of Exile: Refugees Imprisoned in America", 1986 (Box 39, Folder 263)
  - Leadership Conference Education Fund, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 264)
  - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, 1985-1986 (Box 39, Folder 265 - 266)
  - Lefever, Ernest, Circa 1986 (Box 39, Folder 267)
  - Legal Services Corporation
    - Budget, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 268)
    - Chronologies and histories, 1984-1985, undated (Box 39, Folder 269 - 273)
    - Clippings, 1980-1990, undated (Box 39, Folder 274 - 276)
    - Legal Aid Society, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 277)
    - National Legal Aid and Defender Association, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 278)
    - National Organization of Legal Services Workers, undated (Box 39, Folder 279)
    - National Public Radio, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 280)
    - Reports, 1981-1983 (Box 39, Folder 281 - 283)
    - United States House of Representatives, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 284)
    - United States Senate, 1983-1989 (Box 40, Folder 285)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-1989 (Box 40, Folder 286 - 287)
  - Los Angeles Free Press, 1969-1972 (Box 40, Folder 288)
  - Mahoney, Yulick, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 289)
  - Manion, Daniel J. [nominee for United States Seventh Circuit Court of Appeals], 1986 (Box 40, Folder 290)
  - McCarthy, Joseph, 1954, undated (Box 40, Folder 291)
  - Meese, Edwin [civil liberties record], 1985-1986 (Box 40, Folder 292)
  - Mesarosh, Steve
    - United States v. Steve Mesarosh, 1955 (Box 40, Folder 293 - 298)
    - Miscellaneous court documents, 1953 (Box 41, Folder 299 - 301)
  - Minnesota Citizens' Review Commission on the FBI, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 302)
  - Mobilization for Survival
    See: Series III. Subject Files, 1941-1992 Folder 338
  - Movement Support Network
    - Death Squad Act, undated (Box 41, Folder 303)
    - FBI harassment incidents, 1986-1987 undated (Box 41, Folder 304 - 305)
    - Newsletters, [1985]-1988, undated (Box 41, Folder 306 - 307)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1989 (Box 41, Folder 308)
  - National Abortion Federation, 1989-1991 (Box 41, Folder 309 - 310)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Legal Defense and Education Fund, 1982-1986 (Box 41, Folder 311 - 313)
  - National Coalition Against Censorship
    - Censorship News, 1988-1991 (Box 41, Folder 314)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 41, Folder 315)
  - National Committee Against Repressive Legislation, 1981-1990 (Box 41, Folder 316)
  - National Committee to Restore Internal Security, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 317)
  - National Conference on Government Spying, 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 318)
  - National Council for Better Education, undated (Box 41, Folder 319)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America, 1964, 1982-1983 (Box 41, Folder 320)
  - National Educational Television [27 reel-to-reel audio tapes of various sizes and speeds from a series on political surveillance and spying], 1971-1972, undated (Box 42–46)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties [pamphlet: "Witch Hunt, 1941, Hits Government Workers"] (Box 47, Folder 321)
  - National Lawyer's Guild at Yale, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 322)
  - National Maritime Union of America [re: labor spies], undated (Box 47, Folder 323)
  - New York Eight
    - General, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 324)
    - Wareham, Roger [correspondence], 1985 (Box 47, Folder 325)
  - New York State Assembly Special Task Force on State Police Non-Criminal Files, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 326)
  - Northwest Citizens' Defense Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 47, Folder 327)
  - Nuclear Freeze Movement
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 328)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 329)
    - Anti-freeze clippings and organizations, 1982, undated (Box 47, Folder 330 - 332)
    - Clippings, 1982, undated (Box 47, Folder 333)
    - Connecticut campaigns, 1982-1983 (Box 47, Folder 334)
    - Correspondence with Donner, 1982-1983 (Box 47, Folder 335)
    - Government publications, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 336)
    - Helsinki Watch, 1982 (Box 47, Folder 337)
    - Mobilization for Survival, 1981, undated (Box 47, Folder 338)
    - Notes, undated (Box 47, Folder 339)
    - United States and World Peace Council, 1981-1982 (Box 47, Folder 340)
    - Writings [media critique and responses to red baiting], 1982 (Box 48, Folder 341)
    - Miscellaneous peace organizations, 1982-1983 (Box 48, Folder 342)
  - Nuclear Regulatory Commission, 1981-1991, undated (Box 48, Folder 343)
  - Occupational Health and Safety Administration, 1986-1988, undated (Box 48, Folder 344)
  - Ohio Bill of Rights Conference, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 345)
  - Ohio Commission for Smith Act Defendants, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 346)
  - People for the American Way
    - General, 1988, undated (Box 48, Folder 347 - 348)
    - "Government by Litmus Test: George Bush, the Far Right, and Abortion", Circa 1990 (Box 48, Folder 349)
    - Pamphlets, 1983-1986 (Box 48, Folder 350)
  - People's Dreadnaught ["Law Enforcement Agencies Methods of Surveillance"], undated (Box 48, Folder 351)
  - Planned Parenthood Federation of America, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 352)
  - Planned Parenthood of New York City, 1989 (Box 48, Folder 353)
  - Pico-Union 21, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 354)
  - Pinkerton National Detective Agency, undated (Box 48, Folder 355)
  - Political Rights Defense Fund, 1975-1978 (Box 48, Folder 356 - 357)
  - "Private Spies" [KRON Special Report transcript], 1987 (Box 48, Folder 358)
  - Public Citizen
    - General, 1992, undated (Box 48, Folder 359)
    - Health Research Group, 1984-1985 (Box 48, Folder 360 - 361)
    - Public Citizen, et al. v. Frank Burke, et al., 1987 (Box 49, Folder 362)
  - Randall, Margaret J. [deportation case], 1986-1987 (Box 49, Folder 363 - 367)
  - Regnery, Alfred, undated (Box 49, Folder 368)
  - El Rescate Human Rights Department (Los Angeles) [report: "El Salvador Update: Counter-terrorism in Action"], 1987 (Box 49, Folder 369)
  - The Resource Center [Albuquerque, New Mexico], 1985-1987 (Box 49, Folder 370 - 371)
  - Revolutionary Union, 1972 (Box 49, Folder 372)
  - The Roscoe Pound-American Trial Lawyers Foundation. Annual Chief Justice Earl Warren Conference on Advocacy, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 373)
  - "Sanctuary movement"
    - Center for Defense Information, 1987 (Box 49, Folder 374)
    - Clippings, 1983-1989 (Box 49, Folder 375 - 377)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 50, Folder 378)
    - Court documents, 1984-1991 (Box 50, Folder 379 - 389)
    - Old Cambridge Baptist Church, 1984-1986 (Box 50, Folder 390)
    - Salvadoran and Guatemalan Caravan for Peace and Justice in Central America, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 391)
    - Statements by churches, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 392)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981-1985, undated (Box 50, Folder 393)
  - Scalia, Antonin [reports, press releases, and notes], 1986 (Box 50, Folder 394)
  - Schneiderman, William, 1952 (Box 50, Folder 395)
  - Seattle Liberation Front
    - Clippings, 1970-1978 (Box 51, Folder 396 - 399)
    - Legal documents, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 400 - 401)
    - "Making of a Riot, 1970: A Confidential Report on the Birth of the Seattle Liberation Front", undated (Box 51, Folder 402)
    - Notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 403)
    - Press release, [1971] (Box 51, Folder 404)
  - Simon Silverman v. United States of America, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 405 - 407)
  - The Smith Act, undated (Box 51, Folder 408 - 411)
  - Socialist Workers Party [mostly Chicago area]
    - Clippings, 1974-1983 (Box 51, Folder 412 - 416)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 51, Folder 417)
    - Court documents [includes transcripts, exhibits, and final report from Socialist Worker's Party v. the Attorney General of the United States], 1974-1980 (Box 52, Folder 418 - 438)
    - Heisler, Edward
      - Correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 53, Folder 439)
      - Deposition, 1981 (Box 53, Folder 440 - 449)
      - Publications, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 450)
  - Southern Conference Education Fund, undated (Box 53, Folder 451)
  - Teachers Union of New York City, 1953-1954 (Box 53, Folder 452)
  - Treen, David C. [nominee to the United States Fifth Circuit Court of Appeals], 1987, undated (Box 53, Folder 453 - 454)
  - Underground press, 1968, 1970, undated (Box 53, Folder 455)
  - United Nations Administrative Tribunal [brief brought by Donner on behalf of twelve applicants, allegedly dismissed from United Nations contracts for political reasons], undated (Box 54, Folder 456)
  - Vanotti, Paul, 1981 (Box 54, Folder 457)
  - Victims of the Christic Institute, 1988, undated (Box 54, Folder 458)
  - Vietnam Veterans Against the War
    - Camil, Scott [information provided by informers], 1971-1972 (Box 54, Folder 459)
    - Clippings, 1972-1978, undated (Box 54, Folder 460 - 461)
    - Correspondence [between Frank Donner and Nancy Miller], 1974-1980 (Box 54, Folder 462)
    - Court documents, 1972-1984, undated (Box 54, Folder 463 - 466)
    - Informers
      - Becker, Carl and Art Franz, 1972, undated (Box 54, Folder 467)
      - Koehler, William Joseph, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 468)
      - Lemmer, William
        - Correspondence, 1972, undated (Box 54, Folder 469)
        - Information provided by Lemmer, 1971-1973, undated (Box 54, Folder 470)
        - Interviews with Lemmer, undated (Box 54, Folder 471 - 474)
        - Interviews about Lemmer
          - Damron, Mike, undated (Box 54, Folder 475)
          - Donner, Don and Nancy Miller, undated (Box 55, Folder 476 - 477)
          - Hoard, Dr. [first name unknown], undated (Box 55, Folder 478)
          - Jordan, Marty, undated (Box 55, Folder 479)
          - Lemmer, Mary, undated (Box 55, Folder 480)
          - Nelson, D. R., Jr., undated (Box 55, Folder 481)
          - Niles, Clinton, undated (Box 55, Folder 482)
          - Orgen, David, Jr., undated (Box 55, Folder 483)
          - Stocking, Barbara, undated (Box 55, Folder 484)
          - Unidentified, undated (Box 55, Folder 485)
        - Lawsuit against Harper's Magazine, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 486)
      - Poe, Emerson Leroy
        - Information provided by Poe, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 487)
        - Statement about Poe, undated (Box 55, Folder 488)
    - Notes, 1972, undated (Box 55, Folder 489 - 490)
    - Press releases, 1973, undated (Box 55, Folder 491)
    - Television transcripts and interviews, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 492)
    - Writings by Frank Donner
      See: Series IV. Writings, 1950-1992 Folder 4 - 5
    - Writings by Nancy A. Miller
      - Manuscript for "Lookingglass: A Personal Odyssey Through the Nightmare of the Gainesville Eight Conspiracy Trial", 1980 (Box 56, Folder 493 - 503)
      - "Watergate South", 1974, 1981 (Box 56, Folder 504)
  - Walker-McCarran Act, 1951-1955 (Box 56, Folder 505 - 506)
  - Walter-O'Malley Bill ["FBI Files Bill"], 1957 (Box 56, Folder 507)
  - Washington Spectator, 1982-1989 (Box 56, Folder 508 - 509)
  - The Watchtower, undated (Box 56, Folder 510)
  - White House Office of Management and Budget, undated (Box 56, Folder 511)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 512)
  - Working Committee on the CIA/FBI Executive Order, 1981-1982 (Box 56, Folder 513)
- Writings, 1950-1992; Series IV
  The series includes published and unpublished articles, books, book reviews, letters, manuscripts, speeches, and notes written by Frank Donner and a small number of writings by other individuals. Organized alphabetically by type, the writings cover many themes including informers, police and government surveillance, the House Committee on Un-American Activities, civil liberties, civil rights, and the Reagan and Bush administrations of the 1980s.
  Donner's articles include both published works and manuscripts for both published and unpublished pieces. The published articles are divided between those which ran in The Nation and various other magazines. The "Donner/Francis Letters," a published exchange between Donner and Samuel Francis that ran over several issues of The Nation, are filed under the Letters section, which contains letters Donner wrote to various publications. The Manuscript articles are arranged alphabetically by title or subject and include writings on several informers, including Elizabeth Bentley, Winston Burdett, Larry Grantwohl, William Lemmer, Harvey Matusow, and Thomas Tongyai. Some of the manuscripts may overlap with chapters of Donner's unpublished book on informers, filed in the Books section.
  Arranged chronologically, the Books section consists of drafts, notes, reviews, and correspondence relating to Donner's three published and two unpublished monographs. Drafts of the two unpublished works, "Age of the Informer" and "Exploring the Wreckage" provide in depth analysis of the use of informers and of government malfeasance during the 1980s respectively. Many parts of "Age of the Informer" were published in other forms as articles or as part of The Age of Surveillance.
  Donner's handwritten notes on a variety of topics are filed alphabetically by topic under the heading of Notes. One box of miscellaneous note cards is included at the end of the section. The series also includes a small number of Donner's Speeches on topics such as the American right wing, political intelligence work, and civil liberties.
  The final section of the series is Writings of Others, which consists of manuscripts of articles sent to Donner, presumably for his review. The writings are arranged alphabetically by author and the topics mirror the subject strengths of the rest of the collection, focusing on informers, provocateurs, police and government surveillance, the radical right, and civil liberties.
  - Articles
    - Published
      - The Nation, 1954-1988 (Box 57, Folder 1 - 3)
      - Other magazines and journals, 1955-1981, undated (Box 57, Folder 4 - 5)
    - Manuscripts
      - Bentley, Elizabeth, undated (Box 57, Folder 6)
      - Burdett, Winston, undated (Box 57, Folder 7)
      - Campus surveillance, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - "Confessions of a False Witness" [re: Harvey Matusow], undated (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - "Evenhandedness-With a Vengeance" [re: Ramsay Clark], undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - "The FBI Informant", undated (Box 57, Folder 11)
      - Grantwohl, Larry, undated (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - Informers [miscellaneous individuals], undated (Box 57, Folder 13)
      - "Intelligent Student's Guide to Political Investigation, Surveillance, and Informing", 1963, undated (Box 57, Folder 14-15)
      - "L.A. Brutality-When Will It End?", [1991] (Box 57, Folder 16)
      - Lemmer, William, undated (Box 57, Folder 17)
      - "Life Signs of a New McCarthyism", undated (Box 57, Folder 18)
      - "New Orleans: The Police and the Panthers", undated (Box 57, Folder 19)
      - Orans, Alice, undated (Box 58, Folder 20)
      - "Perjured Spies", undated (Box 58, Folder 21)
      - "The Re-emergence of the Provocateur", 1972 (Box 58, Folder 22)
      - "Stoolpigeons", undated (Box 58, Folder 23)
      - "Tommy the Traveler: The Provocateur as Folk Hero", undated (Box 58, Folder 24)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 58, Folder 25)
    - Spanish translations of articles, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 26)
  - Book reviews, 1966-[1992] (Box 58, Folder 27)
  - Books
    - "Age of the Informer" [unpublished]
      - Abstracts and outlines, undated (Box 58, Folder 28)
      - Numbered chapters (I-V), undated (Box 58, Folder 29-33)
      - "The Age of the Informer", undated (Box 58, Folder 34)
      - "Anatomy of Informing", undated (Box 58, Folder 35-36)
      - "Anatomy of Informing", undated (Box 59, Folder 37-38)
      - Budenz, Louis, undated (Box 59, Folder 39)
      - "The Emergence of the American Political Intelligence System", undated (Box 59, Folder 40)
      - "Five Who Recanted", undated (Box 59, Folder 41)
      - "A Look at the Files", undated (Box 59, Folder 42)
      - "No Place to Hide: A Case History of an Informant", undated (Box 59, Folder 43)
      - "Our Federal Police-The Length and Shadow of J. Edgar Hoover", undated (Box 59, Folder 44)
      - "The Politics of Betrayal", undated (Box 59, Folder 45)
      - "Private Surveillance", undated (Box 59, Folder 46)
      - "The Provocateur as Con-Man", undated (Box 59, Folder 47)
      - "The Provocateur Provoked", undated (Box 59, Folder 48)
      - "The Recanter and the Government", undated (Box 60, Folder 49)
      - "Surveillance on Campus: The Informer in Academe", undated (Box 60, Folder 50)
      - "The Theory and Practice of Provocation", undated (Box 60, Folder 51)
      - Additions and supplements, undated (Box 60, Folder 52)
    - The Un-Americans [notes], 1955, undated (Box 60, Folder 53)
    - The Age of Surveillance
      - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 60, Folder 54)
      - Outline, Circa 1979 (Box 60, Folder 55)
      - Promotional material, 1980, undated (Box 60, Folder 56)
      - Reviews, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 57)
    - Protectors of Privilege
      - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 60, Folder 58)
      - Outline, undated (Box 60, Folder 59)
      - Manuscript drafts, undated (Box 60, Folder 60-62)
      - Manuscript drafts, undated (Box 61, Folder 63-72)
      - Manuscript drafts, undated (Box 62, Folder 73-85)